

My Contact

Burhanuddinmarcha@gmail.com

(L) +91-8209407970

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Iinkedin.com/in/burhanuddin49

github.com/Burhanuddin-49

Skills

- JavaScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- Asp.net
- SQL
- MongoDB
- Node.js
- API Integration
- C++
- Python

Education Background

- Dr. D. Y. Patil Institute of Technology, Pune Bachelor of Computer Engineering 2020-2024
- Indian Central School, Kuwait CBSE (Class XII)
 Completed in 2020

Positions of Responsibility

- Computer Society of India (CSI)
 Club Adviser | Sr. Tech Head 2022-2024
- Acunetix 10.0
 Sr. Tech Head
 2022-2023

Burhanuddin Marcha

Software Developer

About Me

I'm a software developer with **2 years of experience in full-stack development**, specializing in Next.js and React.js. I excel at API integration, am a team player, and a passionate problem solver. Eager to adapt to new technologies and contribute my skills to create exceptional software solutions.

Professional Experience

BrsikGrid Solution Pvt. Ltd. | Associate Software Engineer Nov' 2022 - Nov' 2023 (1 years)

Key responsibilities:

- Design and develop web applications using Next.js and React.js
- Implement and maintain API integrations for improved functionality
- Collaborate with the development team to troubleshoot and resolve **technical issues**
- · Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code
- Stay updated on emerging technologies and best practices in software development"

Persistent Systems | Summer Internship

2023 – 2023 (3 Months)

Key responsibilities:

- Comprehensive training in core Java, Linux system administration, DBMS, and data structures & algorithms (C).
- Applied acquired knowledge to contribute to real-world software projects and optimize code.

DevTown | Full Stack Developer Intern

2021 - 2022 (5 Months)

Key responsibilities:

- Received extensive training in web development technologies, including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React.js, leading to the creation of my first web application.
- Independently developed multiple websites from the ground up, utilizing React.js, Redux for state management, and MongoDB for data storage and retrieval.

Projects

<u>Acunetix 10.0 | A college fest website where participants</u> Nov' 22 <u>can register for the event from the website</u>

- Streamlined website navigation for users to easily access event information and registration forms.
- Enabled real-time updates for event availability and registration status.
- Implemented email notifications for event confirmations and reminders for registered users.

<u>CSI Website</u> | A Website built for CSI and CSI Blog using Sanity.io and Next.js.

Mar's 23

- Created a website for CSI and a blog using Sanity.io and Next.js, facilitating club information sharing and blog posts.
- Designed an admin dashboard for easy blog management, enabling admins to upload, edit, and delete content effortlessly.